Guide to the Center for Policy Analysis records, 1987-2006.
Center for Policy Analysis records
- "Women's Voices" project materials. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1997-99., 1997-1999; Document (Box 5, Folder 36)
  6 project documents - #1: Women's Leadership on Affirmative Action: Values, Economics & Opportunities. Western Community Policy & Leadership Forum. State Roundtable. (Seattle, Washington. September 1998). #2: Women At Work: Facts About Working Women. State-by-state Data. (Media Resource Booklet. September 1998). #3: Blueprint for Action - An Executive Summary of America's Economic Agenda: Women's Voices for Solutions (1998). #4: Blueprint for Action Press Release Packet (1998). #5: Women's Economic Leadership Summit Report (1997). #6: Balancing Family and Work: Facts about Working Families. (State-by-state Data. May 1999).
- Community Health Workers: A Leadership Brief on Preventive Health Programs. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1998., November 1, 1998; Policy Brief (Box 5, Folder 37)
  12 sections including description of community health workers (CHW), CHW program components, profiles, results, current research & development, policy funding, actions, etc.,
- 98 Policy Briefing Book: Working to create whole and health families and communities. An Economic Agenda for America: Women's Voice for Solutions. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1998., 1998; Policy Brief (Box 5, Folder 38)
  5 section briefing book including: agenda overview, economic self-sufficiency, health & security, family & work, and entrepreneurship
- The Conservative Agenda in the States: As outlined at the 1999 Annual Meeting of the American Legislative Exchange Council (ALEC). Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1999., 1999; Policy Agenda (Box 5, Folder 39)
  Policy agenda including legislation reviews, newspaper articles, step-by-step actions, & other information
- Leaders Moving Ideas to Action - Summit on the States. Washington, D.C. Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000., December 9-11, 2000; Informational Packet (Box 5, Folder 40)
  Summit informational packet including agenda, participant contact info, panelists bios, evaluation, CPA's Newsletter (Nov/Dec 2000), Women's Voices 2000 & goals sheet
- Siegel, Beth & Kwass, Peter & Reamer, Andrew. Financial Deregulation: New Opportunities for Rural Economic Development. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives & Mt. Auburn Associates, 1986., 1986; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 18)
  4 chapters including: intro, regulatory tools for protecting community credit needs, creating community oriented rural financial institutions, strengthening rural community banks, plus attachments
- Rosen, David Paul. Public Capital. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988., 1988; Series (Box 6, Folder 19)
  3 part book, 9 chapters including: Part I: The Public Capital Agenda. PartII: Public Capital Strategies. PartIII: Coming Home: Reasserting Federal Community Policy
- Ward, Roxnne L.. 1988 Midwest Leadership Profiles (DISPLAY COPY). Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives & The Joyce Foundation, 1988., 1988; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 20)
  State profiles of the midwest including congressmen, committees, legislative priorities, and authored legislation
- Adams, Toni & Tryens, Jeffrey (Ed.). The Pesticides Crisis: A Blueprint for States. Washington D.C.: Texas Center for Policy Studies and National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988., 1988; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 21)
  10 chapters including: intro, registration, food, farm practices, residential & urban uses, silviculture, etc., plus appendices including glossary & about the authors
- Peters, Farley & Stumberg, Robert & Ward, Roxanne. Legislative Sourcebook - Financial Deregulation. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988., 1988; Series (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Book includes sections on: community reinvestment acts interstate banking laws, linked deposits, resources, etc., plus statistical data & findings
- Cohen, Rick. Housing Trust Funds in New Jersey. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1989., 1989; Series (Box 6, Folder 23)
  6 sections including executive summary, intro, national & NJ housing needs, State housing development trust fund experience in the U.S., Sources & Implementation, plus bibliography
- A Policy Guide - Women's Voice's: A Joint Project. Washington D.C.: Ms. Foundation for Women and Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., September 1992; Policy Guide (Box 6, Folder 24)
  4 sections including: preface, decent jobs & wages, easing the squeeze on families, resources plus bibliography
- Totten, Michael & Settina, Nita. Energywise Options for State and Local Governments. New and Expanded 2nd Edition. A Policy Compendium: The Best Programs in: Renewables, Transportation, Energy Efficieny & Waste Reduction. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., January 1993; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 25)
  4 chapters including reviews under the categories of: Energy Efficieny, Land Use & Transporation, Waste Reduction: Reuse, Recover & Recycle, and Renewable Energy, plus appendum, contacts and about the authors
- Various authors. Focus Papers - Child Care, Telecomunications, Motor-Votor. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., June, August, November 19, 1993; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 26)
  3 legislative reports - #1: The Child Care Credit Crunch - A Survey of Lending for Child Care Facilities (Prepared by: Richard Ferlauto, Chris Owen & Deborah Solomon. June 1993). #2: "Motor-Voter" Implementation Overview (By: Burck Smith. August 1993). #3: Issues in Telecommunication and Democracy: A Focus Paper prepared for Telecommunications, Governance and the Democratic Process (November 19, 1993).
- Various authors. Policy Reports. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., Summer, September 1993; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 27)
  2 policy alternatives & reviews - #1: The Fiduciary Duty Aspects of Economically Targeted Investments (By: Lynn A. Bowers. Harrison State Legislation Clinic. Summer 1993). #2: Guideline for State Level Sustainable Development (By: Patricia Scruggs. CPA & The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill's Environment Resource Program. September 1993)
- Toward A Healthier Nation: A Reproductive Health Care Agenda. The Collaborative Project On State Reproductive Health Policy. Catholics for a Free Choice, Center for Policy Alternatives, National Council of Negro Women, National Women's Law Center and Women's legal Defense Fund, 1993., September 1993; Policy Agenda (Box 6, Folder 28)
  4 sections including: participating organizations, intro, the status of reproductive health care in the U.S., a reproductive health care agenda for America's women and families, plus appendices and bibliography
- Policy Reports. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., June, September 24, 1994; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 29)
  3 policy issues reports - #1: Making Capital Access Programs Work In Your State: A Survey of State Capital Access Programs (Prepared by: Richard Ferlauto & Marsha Perry. June 1994). #2: Case Study in Groundwater Protection: Wisonsin's Atrazine Regulation (By: Nan Kim and Tara Zadeh. June 1994). #3: GATT Impact on State Law: California(By: Robert Stumberg with Denis Gooding, Mary Rundle & Gian-Michele a Marca. September 24, 1994).
- Ferlauto, Richard C.. Community capital: jobs from the bottom-up. Jobs and Growth: The International Perspective, 1994., November 1994; Article (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Photocopy of article in larger publication
- Women's Voices '96. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1995., 1995; Memorandum (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Project memorandum including summary of findings, textual analysis and methodology
- Chamberlin, Whitney. Telecommunications & Community Economic Development in North Carolina. Conference Report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives and Benton Foundation, 1995., 1995; Conference Report (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Conference report including about the center, acknowledgements, intro, "why north carolina?", keynote address summaries, applications, goals & future directions, conference agenda, and recent CPA publications
- The Marketplace of Ideas: The States and a Progressive Future - A Consultation with Foundation Executives. Briefing Materials. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1995., March 7, 1995; Policy Brief (Box 6, Folder 33)
  5 sections including reviews under the categories of: overview, 1994 Election Analysis, The Logistics of Legislating in the States, Where are the Progressive Voices?, plus Selection of current clippings
- Various authors. Center for Policy Alternatives' Policy Reports for 1995, June, November, December 1995; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 34)
  3 legislative reports - #1: Investment Intermediaries: Model State Programs (By: Isamu Watson with Rich Ferlauto. June 1995). #2: Environmental Justice: Legislation in the States (By: Ted Robertson. November 1995). #3: NVRA and Beyond: Voter Registration in the States (By: Daniel Schwartz. December 1995).
- Various authors. Center for Policy Alternatives' Policy Reports for 1996, 1996; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 35)
  2 legislative reports - #1: Capitalizing on Collaboratives: New Partners for Community Development Finance (A Report to The Ford Foundation by CPA. July 1996). #2: Source Reduction Roundtable II: Tools for State and Local Programs (Roundtable Report. 1996).
- Directory of Progressive Organizations in the States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1996., 1996; Directory (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Directory including contact info for progressive organizations in the United States
- Various authors. Center for Policy Alternatives' Policy Report & Brief for 1997, May, June 1997; Policy Report & Brief (Box 6, Folder 37)
  2 legislative reports - #1: Community Health Workers: A Leadership Brief on Preventive Health Programs (Note: Handwritten contact information for Lee Rosenthal in the last page of the brief.) #2: Resource Blueprint for California Land Recycling (A Report to the California Center for Land Recycling by CPA. June 1997).
- Render, Meredith. Supporting Self-Employment. A Menu of State & Local Initiatives that Support Microenterprise. Washington D.C.: Association for Enterprise Opportunity, Center for Policy Alternatives and Access to Credita Media Project, 1998., May 1998; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 38)
  5 section report including: intro, menu summary and descriptions, resources, and acknowledgements, plus endnotes
- Tarr-Whelean, Linda (Ed.). A Matter of Simple Justice - Women's Rights Are Human Rights: A Report to American Women and Men on the Occasion of the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1996., 1996; Conference Report (Box 6, Folder 39)
  5 sections of conferene review plus appendices
- Tarr-Whelean, Linda & Mosle, Anne (Ed.). State Venture Policy: Investing in Women Entrepreneurs. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000., 2000?; Policy Report (Box 6, Folder 40)
  2 project materials - #1: Voices of Leadership (Various articles on the issue). #2: 6 chapter pamphlet on issue and agenda topics
- Mosle, Anne (Ed.). Investing in Grassroots Leadership: A State-Based Movement to Amplify Women's Voices for Solutions. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1998., 1998; Memorandum (Box 6, Folder 41)
  Informational booklet including project goals & proposal, policy reviews, participant names of the 1998 Grassroots Retreat, and other info
- Women's Voices 2000: Focus Group Briefing Book. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives and Lifetime Television, 2000., 2000?; Policy Brief (Box 6, Folder 42)
  Briefing book with 5 sections on: Focus Group Key Findings, Focus Group Issue Briefs, Women's Voices 2000 Media Clips, Background on the Polling Project of Women's Voices and About the Advisory Committee and Co-sponsoring Organizations
- Women's Voices 2000: Impacting the Debate. Press Clips, April 2000- January 2001. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000, 01., April 2000-January 2001; Media Publications (Box 6, Folder 43)
  Press clips of the Women's Voices project from April 2000 - January 2001
- Who's Talking? An Analysis of Sunday Morning Talk Shows. Washington D.C.: The White House Project, 2001., December 5, 2001; Research Report (Box 6, Folder 44)
  Research publication - 6 sections including executive summary, academic research, finding & analysis, appendices & tables, methodology, and bibliography
- [no author provided] Business Climate Yields to Growth Climate: The Midwest Pioneers the New Age. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1987., May 1, 1987; Report (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Draft report for the Midwest Leadership Network
- Isensee, Lynne; Tarr-Whelan, Linda. The Women's Economic Justice Agenda - Ideas for the States. Washington D.C.: The National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1987., 1987; Book (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Publication examining economic injustices women face and policy ideas to attempt alleviation.
- Rosen, David Paul. Public Capital. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988., 1988; Book (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Publication examining community disinvestment, options/resources for those community, acts that have addressed disinvestment.
- [no author provided] Barriers to Registration and Voting: An Agenda for Reform. Washington D.C.: Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights, National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1988., April 1988; Book (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Publication examining issues of needed voting reform.
- [no author provided] CPA Annual Report, ca. 1989; Report (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Drafts on each section of an annual report: cover letter, contents, mission and history, national conference description, family and work program, sustainable growth program, public affairs program, overview of 1990 activites, governance program, fund statements, sources, and board of directors.
- [no author provided] Family and Work/Women's Economic Justice Center's 1989 Accomplishments, 1989; Report (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Outline report of program development, publications, and meetings held by the center in 1989.
- Various Authors. City Report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, ca. 1990., ca. 1990; Report (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Report geared toward progressive mayors. Reports past mayors' successful initiatives in order to give current mayors ideas.
- Various authors. Policy Briefs, Articles, Materials for Roundatable, 1992; Collection of materials (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Folder of CPA materials: State Treasurers Policy Brief Expanding Economically Targeted Investments, Pension Funds: A Secret Weapon?, Should pensions be used to improve our society?, Remarks of Commissioner Carol O'Cleireacain, Elements of a Model Bill, Targeted Investment Act - Model Legislation Series, Ways and Means Newsletter
- Gold, Jack. Model Legislation Series: Recycled Content of Newsprint Act. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., Januar 1993; Policy Brief (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Policy brief and description of model legislation for enforcement of recycling newsprint.
- Tammaro, Katherine; Tryens, Jeffrey. GATT and the States. Washington D.C.: National Environmental Enforcement Journal, 1993., December/January 1993; Article (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Article on the effects of an international trade agreement.
- Ferlauto, Richard. Economically Targeted Investments: Rebuilding America's Communities. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., 1994; Briefing book (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Briefing book with memos on leadership roundtables.
- Various authors. Blueprint for Action - An Executive Summary of America's Economic Agenda: Women's Voices for Solutions. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, ca. 1998., ca. 1998; Booklet (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Brief booklet illustrating the gains women have made economically and the continued disparities. Meant for women - an empowering leaflet.
- Various authors. State of the States - Women and Entrepreneurship. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, ca. 1998., ca. 1998; Booklet (Box 7, Folder 13)
- [no author provided] All Publications in Closet as of June 2000. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000., 2000; Report (Box 7, Folder 14)
  List of published reports by the CPA.
- [no author provided] Bringing Capital to Communities. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Leaflet (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Conference forum agenda. Focus on Pension funds, State deposits, endowment funds, and other institutional investments.
- Freedburg, Michael; Slavet, Julie. Residential Energy Conservation and the Low-Income Consumer: Options for State and Local Government. Washington, D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Report (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Report on efforts of specific states to lower energy costs.
- [no author provided] Ways and Means Index. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Index to measure specific initiatives.
- Various Authors. Issue Briefing - Maintaining the Gains: Strategies for State Tax Reform. Washington D.C.: State Issues Forum, National Black Caucus of State Legislators, NCSL Women's Network, 1986., December 3, 1986; Policy Brief (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Critical analyses of federal tax system; suggestions for reform.
- [no author provided] Executive Summary - Center for Policy Alternatives 1990-91 Program. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990-91., 1990-1991; Draft executive summary (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Draft executive summary
- Peters, Farley. Resource Guide for Policy Alternative Leaders. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., May 1992; Report (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Guide of officials, politicians, organizations.
- Zenk, Mary Jo. The Tax Reform Act of 1986: Its Effect On State Debt Issuance for Low-Income Housing. Maryland: School of Public Affairs, University of Maryland, 1987., May 1987; Report (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Act description and analysis.
- [no author provided] Various NCPA documents., [no date provided]; NCPA materials (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Ad Hoc State Tax Coalition information, reports on initiatives, resource list
- Larkin, Richard. Annual Reports Are "Winning" Fund-raising Technique. Rockville: Nonprofit Strategist, 1990., January 1990; Article (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Article describing benefits for non-profits of producing an annual report.